

David Thonnard

Neuroscientist Data-analyst

🎴 July 26, 1985 (37) 🛮 💵

🔽 Leuven, Belgium

+32 498 07 56 51

@ thonnard.david@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/Thonnard

github.com/Thonnard/

About Me —

I am a neuroscientist and data scientist with a biomedical and psychological background. For the past 8 years, I have been conducting preclinical work studying cognitive flexibility. During this period, I have also developped a wide array of statistical and data-related skills. More recently. I have been combining academia with industry.

Languages -

Dutch **English** French Spanish German

Hard Skills -

▲ Laboratory Skills

Neurosurgical lesions

Neurosurgical implantations

IHC/nissl stainings

Brain perfusion/extraction

✓ Injections (IP/SC/IM)

Optogenetics

Flowcytometry

Work Experience

currently **Research Scientist** UCB

In-vivo pharmacology - neurodegeneration - gene therapy

2020-2021 **QA Analyst/Consultant**

Quality Assuruance in the European Distribrution Center (EDC) for Medical Devices (Johnson & Johnson) as consultant for Altran -

Capgemini.

2013-2020 Neuroscientist KU Leuven - Brain and Cognition

Preclinical brain research. Main topic: cognitive flexibility. Lab of

Prof. Dr. Rudi D'Hooge.

2008 Lab technician University Ghent - Dep. of Virology

> Quantification of cellular immunological memory after measles vaccination through intracellular cytokine detection using flowcytometry.

Lab of Prof. Dr. Geert Leroux-Roels.

Education

currently **Advanced Master in Artificial Intelligence** KU Leuven

Engineering and Computer Science

2014-2020 **PhD Neuroscience** KU Leuven

Thesis: Pharmacological mechanisms and telencephalic interactions

involved in neurocognitive flexibility

2008-2013 Master of Science in Theoretical and Experimental Ghent University

Psychology

Thesis: Jouw pijn is mijn pijn, maar... "Does it matter if you're black

or white?".

2005-2008 **Bachelor in Biomedic Laboratory** University College - Ghent

Technology, Pharmaceutical and Biological

Techniques

Thesis: Quantification of cellular immunological memory after

measles vaccination through intracellular cytokine detection.

Grants

01/2020

2014 Doctoraatsbeurs Strategisch Basisonderzoek IWT/FWO

Conferences & Presentations

08/2017 **European Behavioural Pharmacology Society** Heraklion - Greece

Perseverative behaviour in low-dose MK801-treated mice

07/2017 **RIKEN Brain Science Institute** Tokyo - Japan

Impaired reversal learning after NMDA-induced lesions in the PFC-HC

network

05/2017 **Belgian Society for Neuroscience** Ghent

Effect of MK801 on learning and memory

07/2016 **Federation of European Neurosciences** Copenhagen - Denmark

SocietiesCognitive flexibility: Modulation of prefrontal-hippocampal network

VSC - KU Leuven

Certificates and Courses

Scientific Python

03/2020	Introduction to SAS	FLAMES
01/2020	Python for Machine Learning	VSC - KU Leuven
01/2020	Python for Data Science	VSC - KU Leuven

David Thonnard

Neuroscientist Data-analyst

Behavioural Testing

Morris Water Maze

▼ T-Maze

Rotarod

Open Field

Elevated Plus Maze

Touchscreen visual discrimination

Odor discrimination

Computer Skills

R

SAS

Python

☑ SQL

Stata

SPSS

Matlab

✓ C

✓ LaTeX

A Driver's license: B (2004)

Soft Skills



10/2019	Matlab programming introduction		VSC - KU Leuven
10/2019	Linux scripting		VSC - KU Leuven
12/2016	Non-parametric statistics	Leuven Statistics	Research Centre
07/2014	FELASA C - Laboratory Animal Sciences	Biomedical Scie	ences - KU Leuven
03/2010	Vaccinations in the 21st century		Ghent University
02/2008	The tumor micro-environment: new insit therapeutic perspectives	ights and	Ghent University
03/2007	Viral infections during pregnancy and in Disease and bio-safety in the lab	n children.	Ghent University
2007	Kjeldahl method		Ghent University
2004	Business Management		OLVL Highschool

Publications

2021 Effects of orbitofrontal cortex and ventral hippocampus disconnection on spatial reversal learning.

Thonnard, D., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D.'Hooge, R.

Neuroscience Letters, 135711 DOI

2020 Comparison between touchscreen operant chambers and water maze to detect early prefrontal dysfunction in mice.

Van den Broeck, L., Hansquine, P., Sierksma, A., Thonnard, D., Vegh-

Callaerts, Z. & D'Hooge, R.

Genes, Brain and Behavior, e12695 DOI

2019 Differential effects of post-training scopolamine on spatial and

non-spatial learning tasks in mice

Thonnard, D., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D.'Hooge, R. Brain Research Bulletin, 152, 52-62 <u>DOI</u>

2019 NMDA receptor dependence of reversal learning and the flexible

use of cognitively demanding search strategies in mice *Thonnard, D., Dreesen, E., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D'Hooge, R.*

Progress in Neuropsychopharmacology & Biological Psychiatry, 90,

235-244 DOI

2011 Oorzaken en gevolgen van een verhoogd glucose metabolisme bij

kanker

Thonnard, D., Vermeulen, S.

Tijdschrift van de Belgische Vereniging van Laboratorium Technolo-

gen, 38(1), 17-23 DOI

Extra-curricular Activities

